Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to create a coin collect system.
We're also going to make it so if our player character collects 100 coins, they'll get an extra life.
To get started, go over to your player character blueprint and open them up.
Create a new variable and call it coins.
Make this variable afloat and then compile and close this.
In our game, we're going to visually display it map points that our player character has.
If we go to our item image folder briefly close on our engine and attached in this course lecture,
I'm going to include this coin image, drag it into your folder, then right click apply paper to detector
settings.
And then right click Sprite actions and extract sprites.
And change this to be grid.
And change the cell to be 16 and then go extract.
Then if we select all these sprites and make this a flipbook.
So this is going to be the image of our coin.
Next, let's go to our player hard.
And we're going to visually display the amount of coins that we have.
So I'm going to look for a horizontal box.
And track it in here.
For my second horizontal box.
Let's add a padding of toe to the bottom.
That way there's a bit of a gap.
Then in my palette for an image.
And our it into my third horizontal box.
Then I'm going to look for some text.
And I'll truck gets into the horizontal box.
For the image, select one of the coin sprites that we just made.
And expand it in the x axis until it looks a bit normal.
Then for this text block, select it.
And check this is variable and call this on coins.
Then if we go over to the graph.
After we set our lives, we're going to drag in our coins.
So if we look for the coins, text, drag it in and drag off it and look for set text.
And then if we check in, I'll play a beep reference.
And get them out of coins that they have.
And just connect this into here.
And then finally, right click and add custom event.
And this update points.
And we're going to call this custom event whenever our player character picks up a coin.
So if we compile and close this, the only thing left to do is create our COIN blueprint.
So if I go over to my item folder and I'm going to select my Apple pickup and just right click on it
and go duplicate and I'll call this my coin pickup.
Now, the only thing left to do is create a coin pick up blueprint.
So if we right Click and Go Blueprint class, select an actor and call this coin pickup underscore beep.
If we open it up and go ahead and look for a paper flipbook.
Well, the paperclip.
But it's not the coin that we just made.
And let's get it up a bit.
So something like, Oh.
Then go out and look for spare and select spare collision and make sure it fits around our coin.
Then if we scroll down and go to uncompetitive and overlap, uncompetitive and overlap, we're going
to cost to our player VP.
From here, we're going to get the amount of points that they have.
And if this value is ever equal to 100, so if our black actor has 100 points, we're going to give
our player character an extra life and then reset the amount of coins that they have.
So for Branch.
And connect this interview.
But before we do that, if, say, our player character has zero or under 100 points, then we're going
to increase the amount of coins that they have by one.
So I'm actually going to promote this to rebel.
And of reconnect all these notes here.
Then if I drag in my play a beep reference, I will get them out of coins that they have.
Track.
Okay.
And for at.
In the valley.
I'm going to get one and then we will drag up a lot for set points.
And just connect this and do here.
After we do this, we can drag off our BP and get our hard reference, and we will call the update point
text.
Now let's set up what will happen if my character cuts a coin when they have 100 coins.
The first thing we're going to do is make it so I'll play A character has zero coins.
So if I draw game, I play a reference.
I drag up here and look for set coins and I'll set this to be there.
Then the next thing we're going to do is increase the amount of life that they have by one.
So drag up here and we'll get lives.
And our a pick n add here.
I'm going to put one and then I'll drag a pair and look for set lives and just connect the note here.
So we'll get around life that my pair has and increase it by one.
And actually if we go back to our prior hard.
Best to create a new customer account here where we update the players lives.
So right click and add custom event reports.
Update lives.
And connect us with you here.
And when we update our lives, it will automatically update the amount of coins that we have because
this node is connected to here.
So now if I go back to my coin pickup.
I can drag a pet and get my reference.
And I can drive a here and look for update lives and I'll connect this here and go compile so we can
close this and test this all out.
So I'm going to drag in my coin pickup, move it to layer 20.
And let's place five points.
Actually, I just placed three.
And now we play.
We can see I observe coins.
However, if I pick up a coin, I now get one.
Oh, whoops.
I forgot to make it so that if we pick up a coin, we should just it.
So we go back to our coin.
Pick up.
After we pick up a coin, we're going to destroy this actor.
So I drag and destroy actor and also drag and destroy actor.
And now they're go compile and play.
I have zero coins.
If I pick one up, I get one, and then the coin becomes destroyed.
Nice.
Just so that we can test for our life update system is working.
Let's go to our player.
Beep.
Set the amount of coins that they have and make it so they start with 99 points.
And now if I go play, I'll cut my 100th coin.
Now, when I cut my 101 coin by coin should be set to zero and I should get one more life.
So I do that.
I have zero coins and I have one more life.
Nice.
With this, we have set up our coin pickup system.